Nathan B. Bonilla

(808) 268-5695 | NBonilla409@gmail.com | /in/nathan-bonilla/ | https://bonillaproject.com/

Software Developer

A U.S. Navy Veteran with 9 years of experience in Information Technology and working in fast-paced environments. Has a passion for problem solving, training, mentorship and is highly experienced in IT infrastructure. Seeking a career to make a positive impact and further grow skills as a Software Developer.

Technical Skills

Python | C/C++ | HTML5, CSS | JavaScript | React/Vue | Object Oriented Programming | AWS | Server Administration

Professional Experience:

PDX Code Guild, Portland, OR

Mar 2022 – June 2022

Full Stack Development Bootcamp

Excelled in an intensive 14-week Full-Stack Web Development bootcamp focused on building skills needed to succeed as a developer such as data structures and algorithms, front-end design and team collaboration.

- Launched a portfolio website utilizing AWS EC2 services, Django web framework, and vanilla CSS/JavaScript, showcasing programming capabilities and acting as a personal hub.
- Demonstrated a clear understanding of Python back-end implementation with Flask web framework by developing a coding challenges application with RESTful API.
- Developed 9 major full-stack projects utilizing front-end and back-end frameworks, databases, and version control, instilling the key skills of an industry level full-stack developer.

Precision Castparts Corporation, Portland, OR

Jul 2019 - Sep 2020

Computer Operations Manager

Managed a team of four personnel in the operation and maintenance of enterprise data centers comprised of Windows/Linux/Unix servers and responsible for production schedulers, storage area networks, and backup solutions.

- Optimized and automated computer operation tasks, freeing up man hours and migrating the operations team to more crucial roles such as helpdesk.
- Decreased company spending by over \$600k through optimizing vendor contracts, overhauling network infrastructure, and migrating end-of-life systems.
- Administered over 300 Windows, Linux, and Unix systems resulting in the highest levels of availability and performance across all company sites worldwide.

U.S. Navy, Jacksonville, FL

Lead Network Administrator / Technical Control Supervisor

Aug 2013 – Aug 2019

Led a team of 12 personnel in managing ship-shore wide area network systems across five domains consisting of three Cisco routers, six Alcatel switches, 18 Windows/Linux/Unix servers and 130+ workstations, ensuring high availability and maximum security.

- Recognized as the top technician of USS Roosevelt Deployment 2016 for superior performance in professional achievement, extraordinary leadership and technical expertise.
- Managed the installation and upgrades of Windows servers and prevented vulnerabilities through ACAS/Nessus and HBSS, exceeding Naval expectations on all Information Assurance inspections.
- Monitored firewall, HIPS, and SEIM security logs to ensure the highest level of network security and compliance.

Education and Technical Training:

BS – Computer Science (Graduation Date: TBD)

Portland State University, Portland OR

Cloud Application Development

Microsoft Corporation, Lacey WA